NEERAZ SHARMA

SENIOR VISUAL GRAPHIC DESIGNER

83C, Raj Bagh, behind Rajnigandha Appartment, Sahibabad neeraj_shanky@yahoo.com, neeraz.sharma357@gmail.com 9289365634, 8512862159

Dear Sir/Madam,

I am writing this letter to express my interest for Senior post in Graphic designing as advertised on online job portal.

I have started my career as a web designer and graphic designer cum visualiser and then Group Leader and now a days working as a Design Lead in Techbooks International pvt ltd. I have 22 years experience in creative and resourceful Visualiser and Graphic Designer for Print/Digital with proven ability to enhance team performance, Flash presentation, Book covers, Website landing page, youtube thumbnails, Infographics, Catalogues, Advertisement, Leaflets, Website design and Template design for ibooks and digital platforms. Possess a positive and effective style with the willingness to work above and beyond the call of duty. Furthermore, my expert knowledge of Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Adobe XD, Adobe Premiere Pro CC, Macromedia Flash, Corel Draw, HTML, Pre-Press, MS office to create your design Initiatives.

The following are highlights of my skills and accomplishments:-

- Visualising and designing Templates (Coding compatiable) for ipad, ebooks & Digital products
- Illustration creation and Redrawing tables and artwork processing for Wiley, WK, Elsevier
- Designing of covers & advertisements of science journals
- Processing complex Color and B/W Halftone for print & web
- Handling a team of designers and co-ordinating with Manager
- Flash presentations of computer stationary & Peripherals
- Website updations

Portfolio link:

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1LB3abxWOMMET6gZD51R9YAT7N-Q3snK8?usp=sharing

Enclosed is my resume for your review. I welcome the opportunity to discuss with you personally how my skills and strengths can best serve your company. I appreciate your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Neeraz Sharma



INFO

Address:
83C, Raj Bagh,
Behind Rajni Gandha Appt.
Sahibabad (GZB)

Phone 9289365634 8512862159

🔀 Email

neeraj_shanky@yahoo.com neeraz.sharma357@gmail.com

Portfolio link

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1LB3abxWOMMET6gZD51R9YAT7N-Q3snK8?usp=sharing

HOBBIES









NEERAZ SHARMA

SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER/ART DIRECTOR



WORK EXPERIENCE

StudyIQ Pvt. Ltd

Executive Graphic Designer

June 2022 - Present | Gurugram, India

- Designing of Infographics and video thumbnails
- Book covers and images and timeline infographics

Aptara (TechBooks, Inc.)DESIGN LEAD

APTARA

Oct 2012 – June 2022 | Noida, India

- Visualising and designing Templates (Coding compatible) of ipad ebooks & ibooks & for Digital products.
- Images correction, Illustration creation and Redrawing tables.
- Artwork processing for Wiley, WK, Elsevier journals.
- Updations via mail and Habitat platform.
- Visualization and designing of front/back cover and thumbnails.
- Handling a team of Graphic designers.

Thomson Digital Group Leader (Sr. Graphic Designer)



March 2004 – Oct 2012 | Noida, India

- Designing of covers & advertisements of science journals.
- Processing complex Color and B/W Halftone for print & web.
- Handling a team of designers and co-ordinating with Manager.
- Gave training sessions of Graphics.

Flash presentation of Interior Designs - As Freelancer (2001-2010)

Delhi Press Group Sr. Graphic Designer



Feb 2003 - March 2004 | Delhi, India

- Visualizing & designing of Book covers, Pamphlets, Brochure.
- Ads, Newsletter, Posters for Exhibition & Display Board.
- Image creation and editing.
- Website updations (www.vishvbooks.com)
- Flash presentations for Books Fair

Rational Business Corporation

Web/Print Graphic Designer

July 2001 - Feb 2003 | Delhi, India



- Visualizing & designing of Leaflets, Brochure, Banners.
- Ads, Newsletter, Posters for Exhibition & Display Board.
- Flash presentations of computer stationary & Peripherals.
- Website updations (www.desmat.com).

Sepia Graphics Pvt. Ltd

Web Graphic Designer

June 2000 - July 2001 | Delhi, India

- Design, updation, uploading & web promotion of websites.
- More than18 websites designed.
- Designing of Book covers, Stickers



PERSONAL INFO

Father Name

Late Shri S. N. Sharma

DOB

25 JUNE 1978

Gender

Male

Marital status

Married

Language Proficiency

English, Hindi

Interests and Activities

Listening music, Gym

EXPECTED CTC

650000



SOFTWARE SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop

Web/Print layouts, Images creation, Colour correction, Books covers, Ads

Adobe Illustrator

ibooks and Ebooks templates designs, Banner, Brochure, illustrations and creating images for Web/Print layouts

Macromedia Flash

Corporate & Products Presentation

Adobe Indesign

Brochure, Print Design Ads

Corel Draw

Brochure, Books covers, Marriage cards

PRE PRESS

MS OFFICE

HTML

Adobe XD - Beginner

Adobe Premiere Pro CC - Beginner



ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

MBA (IT & Insurance) from Punjab Technical University

Graduation from CCS University

12th from CBSE BOARD

10th from CBSE BOARD



TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION

•

Diploma (2 years) in Art, Book illustration and Graphics, from Shankar's Academy of Art and Book Publishing New Delhi. Certified in Web Master from World Wide Web Institute, New Delhi. Certified in G-tech in printing (Pre-Press) from T.G.C. institute.

22 years experience in creative and resourceful Visualizer and Graphic Designer with proven ability to enhance team performance, presentation, Book covers, Website landing page, Infographics, Catalogues, Advertisement Leaflets, Website designing and FlashPresentations. Possess a positive and effective style with the willingness to work above and beyond the call of duty.

Date:

Place: